<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>black top &#8211; save the 76 ball</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/black-top/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>it&#039;s not too late</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2007 00:34:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.6</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-76BallAmazon-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>black top &#8211; save the 76 ball</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Turn Those 76 Balls On!</title>
		<link>/2007/01/19/turnon/</link>
					<comments>/2007/01/19/turnon/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2007 00:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[76 ball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atwater village]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black top]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[los angeles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier today, Nathan and I were interviewed for a new automotive-themed television series called Black Top, with the 76 Ball on Glendale Boulevard in Atwater Village as the backdrop. The number 76 was not quite in the shot, and Nathan suggested he might go ask the station manager to set the ball spinning. Much to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today, Nathan and I were interviewed for a new automotive-themed television series called <em>Black Top</em>, with the 76 Ball on Glendale Boulevard in Atwater Village as the backdrop. The number 76 was not quite in the shot, and Nathan suggested he might go ask the station manager to set the ball spinning. Much to our shock and delight, the manager agreed, and by throwing just one switch gave the sign a much needed jolt of kinetic energy. We reckon that one of the other switches in the panel would have illuminated the ball, though this would not have been visible in bright sunlight.</p>
<p> And it was this inspiring experience that inspired us to ask you, oh lovers of the 76 Ball, to take a moment whenever you pass a 76 station which still flies its proud orange and blue colors and ask the manager to please make the ball spin. If it&#8217;s dark out, ask that they light it, too. Heck, you can even offer to buy some gas in exchange! There aren&#8217;t many 76 Balls left on their poles, and we fervently believe that every one of them should enjoy however many days, weeks, months or years it has left by spinning and glowing, just like Ray Pedersen designed it to do.</p>
<p> Together we can turn those 76 Balls on. Save the 76 Ball &#8212; it&#8217;s not too late!</p>
<div id="themify_builder_content-206" data-postid="206" class="themify_builder_content themify_builder_content-206 themify_builder themify_builder_front">

	</div>
<!-- /themify_builder_content -->]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/01/19/turnon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
