<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Adam Hay-Nicholls &#8211; save the 76 ball</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/adam-hay-nicholls/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>it&#039;s not too late</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 19:32:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-76BallAmazon-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Adam Hay-Nicholls &#8211; save the 76 ball</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Intersection Magazine feature</title>
		<link>/2006/11/19/intersection-magazine-feature/</link>
					<comments>/2006/11/19/intersection-magazine-feature/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 19:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adam Hay-Nicholls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Intersection Magazine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[STATE OF THE UNION: The campaign to save the Union 76 ball by Adam Hay-Nicholls Having been unbolted from its giant cocktail stick, a large orange ball sways high above Hollywood in the afternoon breeze. Slowly it is lowered by a crane, but four feet from the floor it comes crashing down, smashing into tiny [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>STATE OF THE UNION: The campaign to save the Union 76 ball  by Adam Hay-Nicholls  </p>
<p> Having been unbolted from its giant cocktail stick, a large orange ball sways high above Hollywood in the afternoon breeze. Slowly it is lowered by a crane, but four feet from the floor it comes crashing down, smashing into tiny plastic splinters. The tangerine shards spread beyond the feet of the assembled onlookers &ndash; locals whose view of their Californian town has just been changed. Their sky seems empty without a giant &lsquo;76&rsquo; to guide them home. &ldquo;Please stop destroying American history,&rdquo; says onlooker Kyle Bates, arms crossed, surveying the wreckage on the gas station bay. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s like McDonald&rsquo;s dumping the arches. Just wrong.&rdquo;   </p>
<p> The Union 76 ball has become iconic to Californians. An eye-catching 700-pound illuminated orange sphere with a dynamic blue &lsquo;76&rsquo; font; when your needle is pointing at the red bar there are few more welcome signs. Their dismantling has prompted a boycott petition that has so far been signed by 1,500 gas guzzlers.  </p>
<p> ConocoPhillips, the Houston-based energy corporation, inherited the brand when they took over Unocal&rsquo;s refineries in 2002. Now the branded ball signs are making way for flattened red and blue discs, in order to create a common image among all of their petroleum brands: 76, Phillips 66 and Conoco. &ldquo;We appreciate motorists&rsquo; loyalty to the orange and blue ball&rdquo;, said a ConocoPhillips statement. &ldquo;Though our look is a little different, our commitment to our customers remains the same.&rdquo;  </p>
<p> But Nathan Marsak, author of &lsquo;Los Angeles Neon&rsquo;, reflects the more popular view, countering: &ldquo;Our urban fabric will lose a groovy, sexy element with the disappearance of this turning orb that still speaks &lsquo;progress&rsquo; and &lsquo;fun&rsquo; as opposed to its replacement which resembles some sort of giant tombstone.&rdquo;  </p>
<p> The campaign&rsquo;s chief drum-beater is Kim Cooper, a committed blogger who&rsquo;s a music writer by day and an LA Confidential-era crime tour guide by night. She, like many Los Angeles residents, felt an attachment to the 76 balls when she first saw them coming down. &ldquo;Now a lot of people are choosing not to fill up in their stations,&rdquo; she explains. Kim and friend Nathan Marsak are the writers of the www.savethe76ball.com petition. &ldquo;We want them to stop pulling down the balls and replace those that have been removed,&rdquo; says Kim. &ldquo;We&rsquo;ve been making &lsquo;Please Don&rsquo;t Take Our Balls&rsquo; T-Shirts to support the campaign.&rdquo;  </p>
<p> American&rsquo;s love affair with the orange ball extends to their own cars. Go for a walk in a supermarket car park anywhere out west and you&rsquo;ll see rows and rows of ping pong balls, sat on radio antennas, sprayed orange with an emblazoned &lsquo;76&rsquo;. The marketing promotion reached 17 million driveways.  </p>
<p> While many of those small balls remain, the full size ones that have been dismantled lie in a graveyard dump near Fresno, like the yesco site in the Nevada Desert where neon signs from Las Vegas go to die. But campaigners Kim and Nathan won&rsquo;t let the discarded signs put them off trying to save those that remain. &ldquo;You&rsquo;ve got to get on the battlements and fight the good fights,&rdquo; says Nathan.  </p>
<p> The ball&rsquo;s creator is upset, after fifty years, to finally see his favorite design laid to rest. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t understand why they&rsquo;re changing to that dark red color&rdquo;, says Ray Pederson, a sprightly 80 year-old, still in the ad game. &ldquo;It isn&rsquo;t attractive or eye-catching&hellip; it rather looks like liver.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thanks to Adam and to <a href="https://www.intersectionmagazine.com/" target="_blank">Intersection Magazine</a> for the support!</p>
<div id="themify_builder_content-201" data-postid="201" class="themify_builder_content themify_builder_content-201 themify_builder themify_builder_front">

	</div>
<!-- /themify_builder_content -->]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/11/19/intersection-magazine-feature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
