<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>phil patton &#8211; save the 76 ball</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/phil-patton/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>it&#039;s not too late</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 05:03:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-76BallAmazon-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>phil patton &#8211; save the 76 ball</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NY Times: Condition Orange</title>
		<link>/2006/07/17/ny-times-condition-orange/</link>
					<comments>/2006/07/17/ny-times-condition-orange/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 05:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new york times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phil patton]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[High Beams: Condition Orange By PHIL PATTON Published: July 16, 2006 ONCE, viewed from those movie-star houses high in the Hollywood Hills, the orange ball-shaped signs of Union 76 service stations floated like glowing citrus across the Los Angeles basin. At dusk, the slowly rotating balls looked like pushpins on a map of the city. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>High Beams: Condition Orange </p>
<p>By PHIL PATTON </p>
<p>Published: July 16, 2006 </p>
<p> ONCE, viewed from those movie-star houses high in the Hollywood Hills, the orange ball-shaped signs of Union 76 service stations floated like glowing citrus across the Los Angeles basin. At dusk, the slowly rotating balls looked like pushpins on a map of the city. </p>
<p>Now the orange spheres are winking out, one by one. A corporate image-changing program by ConocoPhillips, which owns the Union 76, Phillips 66 and Conoco brands, is replacing the balls with flat signs as part of a new standardized design for Union 76 service stations. </p>
<p>The 7.5-foot polycarbonate ball, created for the Union 76 exhibit at the Seattle World&rsquo;s Fair in 1962, was designed by Ray Pedersen of the Young &amp; Rubicam advertising agency. </p>
<p>Two California design buffs, Kim Cooper and Nathan Marsak, have created a Web site (savethe76ball.com) to push for preservation of the orange icon and have begun a petition campaign to save some of the signs. </p>
<p>Mr. Pedersen, 80, who heard Ms. Cooper speaking on a radio program, has joined the effort. Michael Madsen, the actor best known for his role in the film &ldquo;Reservoir Dogs,&rdquo; supports their cause, as does the Society for Commercial Archaeology, an organization devoted to roadside architecture. </p>
<p>&ldquo;We are trying to engage them in dialogue to save a few,&rdquo; Ms. Cooper said in an e-mail message. &ldquo;But from our observations, it seems like the remaining Hawaiian balls have been switched off, while a small percentage of the U.S. balls continue spinning, especially along the La Brea Boulevard corridor.&rdquo; She said there were once about 400 Union 76 balls in the Los Angeles area. </p>
<p>Smaller versions of the orange ball are still available &mdash; the ones that attach to automobile radio antennas. Union 76 gas stations began handing out the mini-spheres in 1967, and they can still be bought online at happyballs.com. </p>
<p> (<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2006/07/16/automobiles/16BEAM.html?_r=1&#038;oref=slogin" target="_blank">New York Times</a>)</p>
<div id="themify_builder_content-186" data-postid="186" class="themify_builder_content themify_builder_content-186 themify_builder themify_builder_front">

	</div>
<!-- /themify_builder_content -->]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/07/17/ny-times-condition-orange/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
